RUCHIKA JASHNANI

IDEA MAKER. TRUTH BENDER. COPYWRITER. COMPULSIVE SHOPPER.







Mission-oriented, marketing and communications professional, with well-developed interpersonal skills and the ability to forge strong relationships with stakeholders. Can both lead and work within a team with dedication and make tough calls when needed. I mostly love juggling between marketing and content creation. In my past life, I worked at an ad agency with various brands and created digital content for a living.

EXPERTISE

Crafting Brand Stories Content Engine Commercial Awareness

Pitch Presentations Making Lists Google Suite

Strong Research Skills Understanding of SEO Advanced Excel

EDUCATION

York St. John University, London

Executive MBA, 2021 (Marketing, Finance, Internationalisation)

Indian School of Management & Entrepreneurship, India

PG in Management, Business & Entrepreneurship, 2019

H.R. College of Commerce & Economics, India

Bachelor of Commerce, 2015

EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE WRITER & CONTENT CREATOR

2018 - Present

- Strategised and curated Instagram content for Soulful Binge, Mother Of Bhukkads.
- Digital campaign scriptwriter for Nykaa and Kotak Mahindra Bank.

CREATIVE BRAND STRATEGIST

SCHBANG Digital Solutions | 2016 – 2017

- Curated branding materials (brochures, posters, standees, and digital creatives) for brands like Castrol (Singapore), LinkedIn Talent Solutions, Lodha Properties, Godrej Properties, Nirav Modi, Kaya Skincare, Asian Paints, Hamleys, etc.
- Created 20 ad films or more while debating the future of advertising (Mad Men-style).
- Crafted campaigns after assessing target audience data.
- Managed creative design and copy for digital assets, as well as internal and external communications, including website, social media, PR, and community engagement.
- Made market and competitor analysis reports.
- Took ownership of the tone of voice and shared clickable copy to engage audiences.

In brief, this was a 24-hour Creative Solutions job where I worked as a team player on tight budgets and even tighter deadlines. I lived the agency life! It was one hell of a learning curve that taught me how to mould brands for attention.

BUSINESS INTERN

Auxilior Ltd. in relation with AIESEC, Mauritius | 2014 - 2015

- Studied the impact of startups in local markets of Mauritius.
- Interviewed 18 women startups and developed a Business model with Women Entrepreneurship Team.
- Assisted as an all-rounder for event coordination. It included designing, advertising, budgeting, etc. for fundraising events.

PROJECTS

- Award-winning campaign strategized for Kaya Skin Care #WishWearFlaunt
- LinkedIn Talent Solutions Annual coffee table book, case studies, e-report on Pharma sector(India)
- Won pitches for Pantaloons Hair Oil, Leveza (Sri-Lanka), Asian paints Atmos, Godrej Properties
- Research Paper Certificate by Dr. Rebecca Biggins "Are we selling Visually?"
- Research Paper on "Ageism in Fashion"
- Editor of ISME Magazine

GET IN TOUCH:

ruchika.jashnani@gmail.com +91 9920058807